カカシ隊長！
Captain Kakashi…
（カカシ）敵の様子はどうだ？
What's the enemy up to?
敵どころか　生き物の気配ひとつ
ありませんよ。
There are no signs of life,
even the enemy's.
完全に沈黙しています。
It's completely silent.
（ガイ）どういうことだ？　ヤツらが
あきらめるとも思えんがな。
What's going on?
I don't think they would just give up.
忍の戦いの極意は心理戦ってね。
The key to a shinobi battle is
psychological warfare.
わざわざ
敵に同調するのもシャクだけど→
I don't like doing what
the enemy wants us to do,
休めるチャンスだと思うとしよう。
but we should use this as
a chance to rest.
各自休息をとって
チャクラの回復につとめてくれ。
Everyone, rest up and
recover your chakra!
ただし　見張りは厳重に。
But be on your guard!
半ときごとの偵察も
引き続き行う。
We'll scout the area
every half an hour!
いつ戦闘が
再開されてもいいように→
We must make sure
we're ready to begin
fighting again at any time!
準備は　忘れないように。
以上　解散！
That is all!
ガイ　お前も少し休め。
Guy, you should rest a little too.
この俺様が　この状況で→
Did you think that I could sleep
at a time like this?!
のんびり寝ていられると
思ってるのか！　えっ？
気持はわかるけどね…。
I understand how you feel, but…
Captain Kakashi…
カカシ隊長。
本部から例のものが届きました。
We've received that item from HQ.
うむ。
((穢土転生…　この術は許せない。
Reanimation…
This jutsu is unforgivable!
サイ！　次は　お前の
根の封印術を使う！
Sai, use the Foundation's
Sealing Jutsu.
俺に続け！
Follow my lead!
But I still can't use that jutsu…
（サイ）でも　あの術は　僕には　まだ！
ダンゾウがお前を
かっていたのは確かだろ。
Danzo thought highly of you,
didn't he?
(もう感情を抑える必要はない))
There's no need to suppress
your emotions anymore!
やあ　サイ。
休んでいるところをすまない。
Hey, Sai, sorry to bother you
while you're resting.
いえ。
That's okay.
本部から　これが届いた。
This just came from headquarters.
You need this for
your Sealing Jutsu, right?
キミの封印術に必要なものだろ？
リー！
Lee…
（リー）あっ！
敵でありますか？
Is it the enemy?!
まだまだ　やれそうだね。
It looks like you can still fight.
Yes, sir!
は　はい！
碧い野獣ロック・リーの辞書には→
I, Rock Lee, the Blue Beast,
疲労困憊の４文字は　ありません！
do not know the meaning
of the word "exhaustion"!
キミには　サイのボディーガードを頼みたい。
I want you to be Sai's bodyguard.
封印術の準備中は
どうしてもガードが甘くなるからね。
He won't be able to
defend himself well
while he's preparing
his Sealing Jutsu.
お任せください！
Leave it to me!
この命にかけても　ハッ！　ハッ！　ハッ！
I will risk my life for him!
じゃ　頼むよ　サイ。
I leave it to you, Sai.
は　はい。
Y-Yes, sir.
サイ君　よろしくお願いします。
Sai!
I look forward to working with you!
安心してください。
どんな敵がやってこようと→
Do not worry!
No matter who the foe,
サイ君には
指一本　触れさせはしません！
I will not let them
lay a finger on you!
リーさん…。
サイ君！
– Lee…
– Sai!
僕も　ナルト君やサクラさんを
相手にするときのように→
You can skip the formalities
and call me by a nickname
呼び捨てか
あだ名でかまわないですよ。
like you do with Naruto and Sakura!
しばらく
１人にしてほしいんですが。
I'd like you to leave me
alone for a while…
わかりました。　何かあったら
すぐに呼んでください。
I understand! Call me right away
if something happens!
あの…
少し　よろしいでしょうか？
Do you have a moment?
あぁ　何だい？
Sure, what is it?
サイ君の封印術に関して→
I'd like to hear a little more
about Sai's Sealing Jutsu.
もう少し詳しく
お伺いしておきたいのですが。
そうだね。
Okay.
どこから説明しようかな。
Where should I begin?
彼が根の忍だったのは
キミも知っているだろ？
You know that he used to be
a member of the Foundation, right?
恐らく　きっかけはキミたちの
中忍試験のときに起こった→
It probably all started
when Orochimaru attacked
during your Chunin Exams.
大蛇丸の襲撃ってとこかな。
((ダンゾウ：お前には　この封印術を→
I need you to learn
this Sealing Jutsu.
習得してもらわねばならん。
はい。
Yes, sir…
三代目火影は希代の術者だった。
The Third Hokage was
an unparalleled jutsu user.
しかし　大蛇丸が
穢土転生により復活させた→
But when Orochimaru
used Reanimation
to bring back the First
and Second Hokage,
初代と二代目の火影を→
屍鬼封尽で封印するしかなかった。
he had to seal them away
with the Reaper Death Seal…
自らを犠牲にしてな。
and in doing so, sacrificed his life.
事を有利に運ぶためにも→
In order for things to
work in our favor,
我ら根も強力な封印術を
手に入れる必要がある。
the Foundation needs
a powerful Sealing Jutsu.
しかし　大蛇丸ほどの術者を
封印する術を→
But will I be able to master
a Sealing Jutsu that will
work against someone
as powerful as Orochimaru?
僕が会得できるでしょうか？
お前ならな。
You can do it.
忍には感情は無用のものと→
You've been taught that shinobi
don't need emotions, right?
教え込んできたな。
はい。
Yes…
押さえ込まれた感情は
膨大なエネルギーとして→
Your suppressed feelings create
massive amounts of energy
心の底に溜め込まれている。
deep inside your heart.
その感情エネルギーを解放することで→
By releasing that emotional energy,
封印術は強大なものへと
姿を変える。
your Sealing Jutsu will
become very powerful.
心せよ。
But be careful!
感情の解放は　お前自身が
負の感情の虜になってしまう→
Releasing your emotions
can make you
susceptible to negative feelings.
(危険をともなっていることを))
It can be very dangerous.
The Helmet Splitter: Jinin Akebino
It's time to change shifts.
交代だ。
ああ。
Okay.
どんな様子だ？
変化なし。
How are things?
There's been no change.
It's morning and
they still haven't shown up.
ヤツら現れないまま
朝になっちまった。
静かなもんだ。
It sure is quiet.
嵐の前ってやつかな。
It's like the calm
before the storm.
祭りのあとってことに
なんねえかな？
I hope it means
the festival's over.
E-Enemy attack!
て…　敵襲だ！
They're here!
来たか。
This way!
こっちだ！
逃げた？
He ran away?
くそっ　こっちか。
Damn it! Is he over here?!
Hey… Where did everyone go?
おい…　みんな　どこに？
ぐあっ！
ぐあ～！
いたぞ　こっちだ！
There he is! This way!
アイツら　追い詰めても
戦うそぶりすら見せやしない。
Even though he's cornered,
he doesn't look like
he's going to fight us.
（カカシ）この戦場で敵は寡兵。
The enemy sent
their weaker forces into battle.
木々に紛れて
ゲリラ戦を主体としているようだ。
It seems like hiding in the trees
and using guerrilla warfare
will be their main tactic.
目標を追って
勇んで散り散りになった→
They want us to become bold and pursue
our targets, and once we've scattered,
忍連合を各個撃破。
they'll destroy
the Shinobi Alliance one by one.
悔しいが　再不斬を破り→
I hate to admit it,
but their aim was for us
to become overconfident
after defeating Zabuza!
勝ち気が出すぎたところを
狙われた。
どうする？
このままだとジリ貧だぞ。
What are we going to do?!
Things are going downhill!
一度　態勢を立て直す。
We need to regroup.
各班に最低３班以上の
集団行動を厳守するように→
Send a message to each team
telling them to work with
at least two other teams!
伝令を頼む。
Okay, got it! And what will you do?
ああ　わかった。　で　お前は？
後方の部隊が心配だ。
I'm worried about
the squads behind us.
敵が俺なら　この混乱に乗じて
支援部隊を断つ。
If I were the enemy,
I would use this confusion to
cut off our support squads!
足止めや封印の中核をなす
後方部隊は→
The rear guards are tough and
have the restraints and seals
to fight against Reanimation.
穢土転生に対抗できる
肝の部隊だからな。
ああ　よくわからんが
そっちは任せた。
Well, I don't understand!
I'll just let you handle it!
話は聞いたな？
You heard us, right?!
Send a message to all teams!
各班に伝令を飛ばせ。
Do not pursue the enemy
if you see them!
敵を見つけても深追いはするな。
なるべく固まって
こっちも各個撃破を狙っていく。
Try to stick together and
we'll destroy them one by one!
はい！
（リー）ガイ先生！　遅くなりました。
Yes, sir!
Guy Sensei!
Sorry I'm late!
Hey!
おう！
（カカシ）サイ！　リー！
Sai! Lee!
ちょうどいい　俺に続け。
封印の準備だ。
Perfect timing. Follow me!
We're going to prepare a seal!
はい。
お任せください！
Yes, sir!
You can count on me!
これ以上
ヤツらの好きにはさせない。
We won't let them get their way!
サイ君　キミの封印術の準備には
時間がかかるんですよね？
Sai, it takes time for you to
prepare the Sealing Jutsu, right?
なぜ　それを？
How do you know about that?
実はあのあと　カカシさんから→
Actually, I asked Kakashi
whether it takes time
感情エネルギーを使うには→
for you to concentrate
in order to use emotional energy.
集中に時間がかかると
伺いました。
その間　必ず僕が守ります。
I will protect you while
you're doing that!
土遁　土流壁！
Earth Style!
Rampart of Flowing Soil!
エンスイさん
今のうちに影縛りの準備を。
Ensui, prepare
the Shadow Paralysis!
（エンスイ）わかった。
Got it!
（みんな）うわあ！
見つけた。
I found you…
もう一度。
One more time!
この鈍刀・兜割の前に→
Defending yourself against
the Blunt Blade Helmet Splitter
防御なんて意味ねえんだよ！
is meaningless!
ぼ　防御ラインを…。
Form a line of defense…
どんなガードも俺の前では無意味。
Trying to block me is meaningless.
まだわかんねえようだな？
You still don't seem to understand!
次で終わりだ。
This next attack will be your last!
（カカシ）まだだ！
It's not over yet!
あれは…。
That's…
カカシ隊長！
Captain Kakashi!
まだ終わりと思ってもらっちゃ
困るな。
I hope you don't think
this will be over soon!
サイ君　始めてください。
ああ。
Sai, please begin!
Okay…
サイ君の封印術のお手並み
拝見させていただきます。
Let's see what
your Sealing Jutsu can do!
((ダンゾウ：心せよ　感情の解放は
お前自身が→
But be careful!
Releasing your emotions
can make you
(負の感情の虜になってしまう
危険をともなっていることを))
susceptible to
negative feelings.
It can be very dangerous.
《覚悟は決めた。
I've made up my mind.
しかし　小さいときから→
But I've been told to suppress
感情を殺すようにと
育てられてきた僕に→
my emotions
ever since I was little.
この封印術の会得など
本当に可能なのだろうか？
Is it really possible for me to
master this Sealing Jutsu?
なにより感情を解放するときの
この恐怖に→
More importantly, can I overcome
this sense of fear I have
打ち勝つことが
できるのだろうか？》
when I release my emotions?
((己が負の感情の虜になったか。
You've succumbed to
your negative feelings.
戻ったか。
ダンゾウ様　これは…。
You're back…
Sir Danzo… What is this?
お前の中に溜まりに溜まった
負の感情の大きさを知り→
You must assimilate the mass
of negative feelings
you have pent up within you
and train carefully.
心して修業せよ。
幼き頃より
お前たちを育ててきたのも→
This jutsu is the reason why
I raised you all from the time
you were young.
この術のためでもある。
己の感情を
完全にコントロールしてみせよ。
Try to gain complete control
over your emotions.
(負の感情を解放したうえで
制止してみせるのだ))
Release your negative feelings
and restrain them.
《あのときの僕は
感情を殺しきれなかった。
I couldn't suppress
my emotions that time…
今の僕が　あのとき以上に
感情を殺すことができるのか？
Can I suppress my emotions now
better than I could then?
むしろ　あのときより　ずっと…》
If anything, it's even harder now!
《でも　僕がやるしかないんだ！》
But…
I have to do this!
まだ　この世にも少しは
手ごたえのあるヤツがいたようだな。
I see there's still someone who's
a bit of a challenge in this world.
いくら忍刀七人衆
相手といっても→
Even if you're one of the Seven
Ninja Swords Men of the Mist,
簡単に
勝ちを譲る気はないんでね。
we're not going to let you
win so easily.
フッ…　ほざけ！
Shut up!
《やっかいな目を
持ってやがる…　だが！》
That eye looks dangerous, but…
つばぜり合いに持ち込むだけで
こちらの勝ちよ！
If I thrust my sword
towards you, I can win!
兜割をガードする方法なんて
ねえのさ！
There's no way to block
my Helmet Splitter.
誰が守るって言った？
Who said anything about blocking?
ガードが甘いよ！
Your defense is weak!
１人目。
One down!
エンスイ！
はっ！
Ensui!
Yes, sir!
封印の準備が整うまで
影縛りで　コイツをおさえてくれ。
Hold him with Shadow Paralysis
until the seal is ready.
わかりました。
Understood.
他の者は　前方の部隊と合流だ。
俺についてこい！
The rest of you, group up with
the squad in front. Follow me!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
影縫いの術！
Shadow Stitching Jutsu!
なるほど　シカマル君と同じ
秘伝忍術ですね。
I see…
It's the same kind of hidden
ninjutsu that Shikamaru uses.
一時しのぎさ。　印が解けるだけで
自由にしちまう。
This is only a stopgap measure.
If I undo my seal, he'll be free.
早いとこ
ちゃんとした封印を頼むぜ。
I hope you can seal him away
as soon as possible.
((そんな…。
Impossible…
（シン）逃げろ　弟よ。
こんな体だ　お前に勝ち目はない。
Run away, little brother.
Our bodies are indestructible.
There's no way you can win!
シン兄さん…。
Shin…
(兄さん　しっかりして！))
Brother, snap out of it!
Secret Black Technique!
Salamander!
((カンクロウ：黒秘技　山椒魚！
(兄さん！))
Brother!
サイ君。
Sai…
《大変だとは聞いていましたが
本当に苦しそうですね》
I heard it was difficult,
but he really looks
like he's suffering.
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
リー　来るぞ！
Lee…
Someone's coming!
爆遁使い！
An Explosive Style User!
《まずい！》
This is not good!
（エンスイ）サイ！
Sai!
封印を急いでくれ！
リー１人では厳しい！
Hurry up with the seal!
Lee can't handle this by himself.
俺も援護にまわりたい！
I need to assist him!
（リー）心配ご無用です！
There's no need to worry!
暁のヤツら　許せません！
I won't forgive the Akatsuki!
死者を穢土転生で
いたずらに操って！
They're controlling the dead
using Reanimation.
僕は本気で怒ってるんです。
I'm seriously mad.
そんな僕が負ける
理由があるでしょうか！？
Is there any reason
why I would lose?
いや　ありません！
No! There isn't!
うお～っ！
《なぜだ　リーの怒りの感情からは
負の感情が伝わってこない。
How?
I don't sense any negative feelings
coming from Lee's anger.
なぜだ　あの怒りは負の感情から
きてるものじゃないのか？》
Why? Doesn't anger come
from negative feelings?
（エンスイ）ぐわっ！
《まずい！》
This is bad!
よくも　よくも僕の仲間を
傷つけてくれましたね！
How dare you…
How dare you harm my friend!
((敵が動き出したようです。
The enemy is on the move.
僕たちも
そろそろ本隊に合流しましょう。
We should regroup with
the main company!
サイ君　僕にできることなら
なんでも言ってください。
Sai!
If there's anything I can do,
let me know!
精一杯　頑張らせてもらいます。
I'll do whatever I can!
(友達ですから))
I'm your friend, after all!
《そうか。
I see…
I see… The source of Lee's anger
is his feelings for his friends.
リーの怒りの源となる感情は
仲間を思う心から。
しかし　そんなことが
この僕に　いや。
But I can't do that…
No!
あのときの自分とは違う。
I'm different from how I was then.
I have friends now.
今の僕には仲間たちがいる。
そして今　その仲間たちに対して
さまざまな感情が生まれている》
And now, I have a lot of
feelings towards those friends.
《感情を解放することで
パワーが上がる封印術。
A Sealing Jutsu that becomes
more powerful
when I release my emotions.
しかし　その感情は
怒りや悲しみの→
But those emotions don't have
to be negative ones
負の感情じゃなくても
よかったんだ》
that come from anger or sorrow!
ホワァチャー！
サイ君。
Sai!
リー　まだキミには
あだ名をつけてなかったね。
Lee…
I still haven't given you
a nickname, have I?
この戦争が終わるまでに
考えておくよ。
I'll think of one,
once this war is over.
サイ君　やってください！
Sai! Do it.
封印術　虎視眈弾！
Sealing Jutsu…
Crouched Tiger Bullet.
《よし　捕らえた　戻れ》
《どんなガードも…》
あ！
待て　深追いはするな。
（リー）サイ君。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手→